#### Marcelo Hussein

Ottawa 736, Tortuguitas Cp 1667 Phone 02320570892 Cell +5491159127871



#### hussein.marcelo@gmail.com

"Marcelo, when I had interaction with him, worked as a technician maintenance SR cellular networks. Surely, at this point, and based on their learning ability and performance, chords to be fulfilling functions which acquired expertise. Always been a proactive person with solving capacity and which provided a high value-added jobs that will play performed. Actually, it a person recommended, highly reliable and an absolute commitment to everything he touches carry forward. I am quite sure, you can achieve any goal that is proposed, both technical and management level. I believe it can lead to projects or join important in any working group. "

- Christian Villarino, Maintenance Supervisor Access Network, Network Miniphone ACE has Marcelo indirectly supervised IBM Argentina.

"Marcelo is known for its level of commitment and professionalism with which manages its tasks. Know understand customer needs and adapt to them, providing the solutions sought by the customers.

Also remarked his positive

#### Professional Profile

# Data Center Infrastructure Specialis & Physical Security Owner

SDC Infrastructure, Physical Access Control IBM SSA

Division Manager - Power Systems ZTE Arg

Responsible for sales, presales and post-sales technical energy solutions ZTE Corp, for Datacenters, Cell Phones, Sites ECP (Centers for Disease Control and switches), and Switched Network Systems,

systems both conventional and renewable energy.

Data Center Project Manager at Telecom Argentina (Multiple Sites scheme) Responsible for the design, implementation and management of technical equipment and civil works for the expansion

and empowerment of the data center and distribution TELECOM ARGENTINA, updating and planning

Future projects and investment in site.

Expertise at DC / AC (rectifiers, inverters, UPS, batteries, Struts)

Preparing general specifications.

Preparation of technical specifications.

Analysis of technical bids.

Calculation of energy systems for data center deployments.

Budget preparation.

Detailed engineering for the work environment.

Special projects for customer implementations within datacenter.

Energy measurement and supply systems.

Planning high-risk tasks for the system connections and replacement of equipment.

Engineering, planning and monitoring of works

Works performed:

Repowering UPS systems in Data Center

for TELECOM.

Repowering and standardization of HSBC sites, UP, Garbarino, OSDE, Arcos Dorados, GOL and others

Design and implementation of operational space boards Data Center.

Redistribution of power transmission systems in the Data Center

All projects were implemented following the TIA, IEC, ANSI.

attitude and perseverance with which he has taken his role within the company. "

## - Maria Jimena Hoses Vergara HR Manager, ZTE Corporation South America, has worked directly ZTE Corporation Marcelo in Argentina.

"In addition to the deep understanding of the technical issues that drive, highlight its seriousness and care in the Final product quality to deliver."

## - Daniel Piechotka, Marcelo has been client.

"Marcelo excels in identifying needs for improvement and evaluation of solutions SYSTEMS ENERGY, environment particularly in telecommunications projects. It is also very good BBQ, and culinary host."

### - Luis Alberto Nacucchio, Engineer, Telecom Personal,

"Marcelo is currently leading various Power projects in ZTE and since joining has noticed a huge difference in the satisfaction of our customers. It has a huge technical strength, which plus work experience make it a key person to carry out projects in timely manner. Mr. Rapetti Andres Project Manager - ZTE Corporation Argentina "

Andres Rapetti, Sr. Project Manager, ZTE Corporation Argentina, has worked directly with Marcelo in Group-SMS.

## Cellular Networks Operations

Redistribution remote stations Edge Switches, reallocation of frequencies, optimizations of network coverage, spectrum frequency Assignment operators 2G networks and 3G Optimizing sites.

## **Specialties**

Experience in monitoring facilities of telecommunications equipment, satellite links,

Switching stations, power systems engineering.

Engineering and supervision of upgrading systems of high power UPS.

Engineering environment for start-up Data Center.

Monitoring and performance testing of transmission equipment for Data Center. Approval of equipment

## Education, Honors, and Certifications

#### UTN

Alternative Energy, 2008 - 2008

Activities and Societies: Training in Solar Energy, Wind, Thermal

#### PUCC Chile

Strategic Decisions 2013

Evaluation of strategic alternatives for implementation according to application markets

National Technological University

2004 - 2007

Activities and Societies: Civil Engineering, Alternative Energy. UTN

#### **Civil Engineering Key Qualifications**

#### Technical SSr

Miniphone

Basic RF, Radio Operation and MaintenanceERICSSON

Bases, Bases Advanced Radio, central installation

AXE, Commissioning

#### Supervisor

Distelco SA

Installation and Commissioning of satellite dishes

**IMPSAT** 

#### Performing Engineering

TELECOM PERSONAL SA

NGN Communications Systems

ITBA

Senior Analyst Environment and Data Center

Telecom

High Voltage

**MONTERO** 

Technical SSr

Red Miniphone ACE SA

Introduction to SDH systems IP Link

Marcelo is a very good professional committed to the result and always motivated"

- Augusto Lamas, Senior Analyst / Technical Manager, Telecom Argentina, has worked with Marcelo Group-SMS.

"Excellent professional treatment with a strong focus on results"

- Gustavo Cyan, Marcelo has been client.

"Marcelo is a good and skilled professional who has always supported my team every time I have needed. I always have demostrated to be highly oriented to customer satisfaction and results achievement."

- Mariano Piro, NOC Manager, Miniphone, Marcelo has supervised indirectly in Group-SMS.

"Marcelo is a great professional, highly trained and proficient in their field. Excellent person"

Roberto Szenkman,
 Commercial Engineer,
 Storage Arizona Marcelo has worked in
 Grupo-SMS.

"Marcelo has demonstrated thorough knowledge and professionalism in the work I have had the opportunity to share. Its high level of knowledge and its cordial greeting, conveys a strong sense of peace and security in a especiaidad where errors tieen no margin."

- Oscar Narduzzi, O & M RESPONSIBLE FOR ENERGY AND CLIMATE CONTROL SYSTEMS, TELECOM PERSONAL / TELECOM ARGENTINA, Marcelo has **STRATEX** 

### **Employment**

## Data Center Infrastructure Support LA Region at IBM Argentina

October 2012 - Present (16 months)

Energy design and distribution, power upgrading & planning for future projects and site investments).

Specializing in Power DC / AC (rectifiers, inverters, UPS, batteries, struts General Preparation of specifications.

Preparation of technical specifications.

Analysis of technical offers.

Calculating the size of plants.

Preparation of budget.

## Physical Access Owner Latin America Region 26 recommendations available upon request Project leader at Data Center

*July 2011 - Present (1 year 11 months)* 

Energy design and distribution, power upgrading & planning for future projects and site investments).

 $Specializing \ in \ Power \ DC/AC \ (rectifiers, \ inverters, \ UPS, \ batteries, \ struts$ 

General Preparation of specifications.

Preparation of technical specifications.

Analysis of technical offers.

Calculating the size of plants.

Preparation of budget.

Address book.

Detailed engineering for work environment.

Special projects.

Energy measurement in power.

Scheduling tasks at high risk for system connections and replacement of equipment.

NETWORK engineering follow-up plan of frequency spectrum of frequency to 2G and 3G operators meeting.

Optimization of sites.

Refine Edge interswitch, remote stations reallocation of frequencies, coverage optimizations.

### Power Engineering Projects Manager at ZTE Corporation

*July 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 4 months)* 

Performing Engineering for TLC Center environment.

Project leader for Data Center (Energy design and distribution, power & planning for future upgrading projects and site investments).

Specializing in Power DC/AC (rectifiers, inverters, UPS, batteries, struts General Preparation of specifications.

Preparation of technical specifications.

Analysis of technical offers.

Calculating the size of plants.

Preparation of budget.

Address book.

Detailed engineering for work environment.

Special projects.

#### worked with Group-SMS.

"Marcelo in the time we worked together in the company, has proven to be very reliable in all that undertook and / or assigned to him, especially in engineering projects, seems to me an excellent and professional colleague. Always attentive to all needs, and to comply in a timely manner which is charge. As for the staff, very good companion, very diplomatic and above all, excellent interpersonal relations with all. "

- Leonardo Damian Prattico, Maintenance Engineer, Telecom Argentina, has worked with Marcelo Group-SMS.

"Marcelo: is an outstanding professional with plenty of planning, is responsible extemadamente and efficient, able to develop a project from design to implantanción, has extensive experience in the area of infrastructure. You can integrate or easily lead teams through its human warmth. No doubt if I had to work on a major infrastructure project scale. I would like to have him. "

- Ricardo Corbalan, Project Manager (Data Center Infrastructure), Telecom, Marcelo has worked in Grupo-SMS.

"During the time that contain Marcelo on my team showed excellent technical competence and concern continuing to accept new Energy measurement in power.

Scheduling tasks at high risk for system connections and replacement of equipment.

#### Senior Analyst Environment and Data Center at Telecom

*November 2010 - October 2011 (1 year)* 

Development and implementation of central projects for TELCO and Environment Data Center

Implementation of power plants and UPS High Power.

## Senior Analyst Environment and Data Center at Telecom Personal Argentina

*November 2010 - July 2011 (9 months)* 

Development and implementation of central projects for TELCO and Environment Data Center

Implementation of power plants and UPS High Power.

#### Performing Engineering at TELECOM PERSONAL SA

March 2006 - July 2011 (5 years 5 months)

Technical SSr at Red Miniphone ACE SA

*October 1999 - March 2006 (6 years 6 months)* 

Access Engineering

Frequency Plan for TDMA

Implementation of TDMA Based stations

*NETWORK* engineering follow-up plan of frequency spectrum of frequency to 2G and 3G operators meeting.

Optimization of sites.

Refine Edge interswitch, remote stations reallocation of frequencies, coverage optimizations

#### Network Engineering at Red Miniphone ACE

October 1997 - March 2006 (8 years 6 months)

Network Administration and deployment of cellular TDMA, GSM

#### Technical SSr Miniphone at

October 1997 - October 1999 (2 years 1 month)

Performing preventive maintenance and corrective TDMA based stations.

Registration of new systems

Construction supervision.

#### RBS installer at SECOR Communications

*May 1994 - September 1997 (3 years 5 months)* 

SDH installing telecommunications equipment, antennas, power)

Installing for Telecom / Telephone links basic single channel for rural telephone service.

Assembly of radiating systems, satellite dishes up to 12 feet.

Working at height

Topographic surveys.

Ground works.

#### Engineering installation of networks at Distelco SA

March 1993 - September 1997 (4 years 7 months)

Engineering and installation of Networks for IBM, deployment of RED for Banco

challenges. Marcelo is a person that seamlessly integrates the computer being collaborative, entrepreneurial and focused on espíriu to efficient .. "

- Pedro Mario Giuffrida, Exploitation and Maintenance Manager, Network Miniphone ACE has supervised Marcelo indirectly in Group-SMS. de la Nacion Argentina

## Supervisor at Distelco SA

May 1993 - September 1994 (1 year 5 months)
Satellite dish installer in seats C and Ku to IMPSAT
Engineering and turnkey installation of level 5 for IBM Network

END

Marcelo A. Hussein DNI 22350343 Phone 02320570892 Cell +5491159127871

Email: <u>hussein.marcelo@gmail.com</u>

Argentina